Hello, everyone, and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine, and today we have the
beginning of a very long series on giving
a presentation.
So the series is at the
intermediate level, right, Marco?
That's right.
It's part of our business series.
We previously took a look at
how to go upon an interview.
Now we're going to
talk about presentations.
So everything about
a presentation, how to
give a presentation,
language you can use in
a presentation, and a lot
of other things like this.
That's right.
So today we're going to talk about
the very beginning of a presentation.
Let's take a listen to this dialogue,
and we'll be back in a moment.
Can you guys sit the back here, everything?
I think all of you know why
we are here this afternoon.
As most of you are aware, 2010 marks
an important moment for alpha computers.
We have bounced
back from the recession,
and now we are set to launch our new
line of laptop and desktop computers.
I'm really pleased to
welcome Michael Ford, the
global marketing manager
for alpha computers,
who has flown in from
California to give all
of you an overview of
the marketing campaign,
and to answer any
questions you may have.
So please, give a warm welcome to Mr. Ford.
Thank you, Jonathan.
It really is a pleasure to be here today.
It has been three
years since I visited
Beijing, and it's clear
to me that operations
here are obviously going
from strength to strength.
The alpha brand continues to
grow in leaps and bounds in China,
and that is certainly down to
the hard work of all of you here.
So congratulations to all of you.
I'd like to start by
outlining the key points
of my presentation this
afternoon, and giving
you an idea of the topics
that we'll be discussed.
The presentation today is
divided into five main parts.
First of all, I'd like to briefly touch on
the background of the new X4-20 line, how
the whole concept has
come about and how
the new product fits into
our existing brand line.
Secondly, I'd like to present data
on projected sales for the X4-20.
We will then go on to discuss our key rivals
in this sector, then I'd like to go on
to outline the campaign
concept for the X4-20.
Finally, I'm happy to
open up the discussion
for any questions or
points you may have for me.
All right, we're back.
As you can see, it's the very
beginning of a presentation.
We're kind of starting to give people
an idea of what we're going to talk about.
Let's take a look at some of the language
Mr. Ford used on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
The reason Mr. Ford
is giving a presentation
is because he wants to talk about
the company's new line of computers.
He says that they're going to launch a
new line of desktop and laptop computers.
That's right.
They want to launch a new line of laptops.
This verb to launch means
to bring out to the market.
That's right.
Instead of the word to
start, which you could
use in many different
ways, to start eating
or to start swimming,
in this case, to launch
means you're going to introduce a new
product to the market like you said, Marco.
That's right.
We are going to start selling
to the market a new product.
We're going to launch a new line
of laptop and desktop computers.
For example, this spring Steve Jobs
launched the iPad, which is a new product.
That's right.
So he launched the iPad and the iPhone 4.
They're always launching
new things at Apple.
That's right.
All right.
So since they're launching this new
line of laptop and desktop computers, Mr.
Ford first wanted to give a brief
overview of the marketing campaign.
Okay.
So first of all, we're going to talk
about how this product is being marketed.
So you want to give
a general picture or a
very simple picture of
what's going to happen.
So at the beginning, this will happen,
then this will happen at the end.
This will happen.
And that's what we call an overview.
That's right.
So it's a brief or general idea of
what we're talking about in an overview.
Nothing too specific.
You just want to give you a general idea.
That's right.
After that, Mr. Ford
starts talking and he's
talking about the presentation,
which has many parts.
And he wants to talk about
what each part will contain.
So he says, I'd like to briefly touch on
the background of the new X420 line.
So this verb to touch
on, what does this mean?
Okay.
So when he says he
wants to touch on the
background of this new computer, he's
basically saying, I want to talk about.
All right.
This is potentially very
confusing because we
know the word to touch means
to put your hand on something.
But to touch on, this is a phrasal verb.
This means to talk about or to address.
That's right.
So for example, a
teacher at a university
will touch on many
topics during his lecture.
That's right.
Or I'd like to touch on where we're going
to dinner tonight because I'm very hungry.
Okay.
So basically it's a nice way of
saying I want to talk about this topic.
And then apart from
touching on the background
of the new computer,
he said he also wants
to talk about projected
sales for this new computer.
Okay.
So projected sales,
this phrase includes two
word sales means how
much of something you
sell obviously, but projected
means what you expect to sell.
So the projected sales
have not happened yet.
They will happen in the future.
And so they're basically
my guess about sales.
That's right.
So basically we are giving an
estimate of what we think we will sell.
Those are projected sales.
We think we will sell a thousand computers.
Those are our projected sales.
Right.
And after that, we have one more key word.
This word comes at the
very end of the speech.
Mr. Ford says we will then
go on to discuss our key rivals.
Now who is a rival Marco?
Okay.
So a rival is basically your competitor
or maybe kind of your enemy.
All right.
So even computers, who is Apple's rival?
Maybe HP or IBM or Dell.
Very good.
So a rival is someone you compete with.
That's right.
So he's going to talk about his key rivals.
So basically the word key
is your most important rivals.
All right.
So for example, who is
one of Batman's key rivals?
Because we have rivals not
just in business, but also in life.
That's right.
I think maybe Batman's
key rival might be the Joker.
Or the penguin.
Yeah.
All right.
So let's take another
listen to today's
dialogue and we'll be back in a
moment with some very important phrases.
Hi, everyone.
Can everyone hear me?
Can you guys sit the back here, everything?
I think all of you know why
we are here this afternoon.
As most of you are aware, 2010 marks
an important moment for alpha computers.
We have bounced back from
the recession and now we are set
to launch our new line of
laptop and desktop computers.
I'm really pleased to
welcome Michael Ford, the
global marketing manager
for alpha computers,
who has flown in from
California to give all
of you an overview of
the marketing campaign
and to answer any
questions you may have.
So please give a warm welcome to Mr. Ford.
Thank you, Jonathan.
It really is a pleasure to be here today.
It has been three years since I visited
Beijing and it's clear to me that operations
here are obviously going
from strength to strength.
The alpha brand
continues to grow in leaps
and bounds in China and that is certainly
down to the hard work of all of you here.
So congratulations to all of you.
I'd like to start by
outlining the key points
of my presentation
this afternoon and giving
you an idea of the topics
that we'll be discussed.
The presentation today is
divided into five main parts.
First of all, I'd like to briefly touch on
the background of the new X420 line.
How the whole concept
has come about and how the
new product fits into
our existing brand line.
Secondly, I'd like to present data
on projected sales for the X420.
We will then go on to discuss
our key rivals in the sector.
Then I'd like to go on to outline
the campaign concept for the X420.
Finally, I'm happy to
open up the discussion
for any questions or
points you may have for me.
All right.
So we've prepared three phrases for you.
Let's take a look at those
now on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
So this first phrase
is really important
because it's about the part of the speech
that happens before the speech begins.
Usually you have a
person who's going to talk
about something, but you also have
someone who introduces that person.
That's right.
On, he's going to talk
about computers, he's
very smart, listen to
everything he says.
So we usually hear the phrase,
"Let's give a warm welcome to."
Yes, this is a very nice
way of presenting someone.
So obviously this person is talking to a
group of people and he's introducing Mr.
Ford.
So he says, "Let's give a
warm welcome to Mr. Ford.
" So that's saying, "Let's
clap, let's say hello to him.
" That's right.
So like you said, this
is an invitation to clap.
You have to clap when you hear this.
Warm welcome means, "Let's be nice
to him, let's all smile and encourage him.
" You know, you think about it.
Someone who's going to give
a speech is probably nervous.
So this helps them feel comfortable.
That's right.
So it's a very nice
way if you're maybe
presenting someone
who's going to talk, you can
say, "Let's give a warm welcome
to whoever you're presenting.
" Okay, now when Mr. Ford
was talking, he mentioned
this very interesting
phrase about operations.
He said, "It's clear to
me that operations here
are obviously going
from strength to strength."
Okay, so that means things are going well.
You do one thing, you
do it well, you move on
to another thing, you
do that well as well.
Okay, so that's what it means
from strength to strength.
So we're saying that things are going from
good to better and getting better, okay.
And what about our last phrase?
Our last phrase is kind
of similar to the last one.
The alpha brand continues
to grow in leaps and bounds.
All right, so you can have
a company that grows
a little, you can have
quite a bit, then you have a company
that grows in leaps and bounds.
That means a lot.
Okay, so to leap is to jump, right?
That's right.
So this is what we're
saying, we're just
jumping higher and higher, we're getting
bigger and bigger and better and better.
That's right.
So this is an
exaggeration, it's like saying
that it's not going
quickly, it's going the
speed of light, you know, it's just so
fast, all of a sudden just really growing.
Okay, a lot of interesting
phrases there, a lot of key vocab.
I think we can listen to this dialogue
again and we'll be back in a bit.
Hi everyone, can everyone hear me?
Can you guys sit the back here, everything?
I think all of you know why
we are here this afternoon.
As most of you are aware, 2010 marks
an important moment for alpha computers.
We have bounced back
from the recession and
now we are set to launch our new
line of laptop and desktop computers.
I'm really pleased to
welcome Michael Ford, the
global marketing manager
for alpha computers,
who has flown in from
California to give all
of you an overview of
the marketing campaign
and to answer any
questions you may have.
So please, give a warm welcome to Mr. Ford.
Thank you Jonathan.
It really is a pleasure to be here today.
It has been three years
since I visited Beijing
and it's clear to me
that the operations
here are obviously going
from strength to strength.
The alpha brand
continues to grow in leaps
and bounds in China and that is certainly
down to the hard work of all of you here.
So congratulations to all of you.
I'd like to start by
outlining the key points
of my presentation
this afternoon and giving
you an idea of the topics
that we'll be discussed.
The presentation today is
divided into five main parts.
First of all, I'd like to briefly touch on
the background of the new X420 line.
How the whole concept
has come about and how the
new product fits into
our existing brand line.
Secondly, I'd like to present data
on projected sales for the X420.
We will then go on to discuss
our key rivals in the sector.
Then I'd like to go on to outline
the campaign concept for the X420.
Finally, I'm happy to
open up the discussion
for any questions or
points you may have for me.
All right.
So as we mentioned,
this is the first part of
a 10-part series all about public
speaking, giving a presentation.
We're going to talk
about many aspects of a
presentation like charts
and graphs and using
PowerPoint, all these really
modern ways of giving a presentation.
That's right.
And we're going to try
and talk to you about
some of the places and presentations that
English learners tend to struggle with.
It's sometimes very hard to know
what to say, especially in today's lesson.
How do you introduce
someone in a presentation?
It's not very common
to learn how to say that.
We hope that through
these podcasts, you'll
be able to learn some
really important phrases
and become more comfortable while
you're giving presentations in English.
That's right.
Of course, if you have
any questions about these
lessons or any of our lessons, you
can always find us at Englishpud.com.
You can send us all your suggestions
about any lesson topics you may have.
That's right.
So we hope to hear from you.
Please let us know what you're thinking.
And until next time, everyone.
Bye.